Guide to the Victor H. Paltsits Papers 1825–1952 (bulk, circa 1890–1952) MS 477.1
New-York Historical Society
- Series II. Research and subject files, 1888–1952
  - Subseries II.B. Research and subject files processed 2020
    - Queens Borough Seal and the Seals of New York, 1948 October 8 (Offsite-box 60, Folder 12)
    - Sale of Manhattan Island in 1626, 1903–1918 (Offsite-box 60, Folder 13)
    - Theater, 1916, undated (Offsite-box 60, Folder 14)
- Series III. Diaries, 1891–1949
  Items are listed chronologically.
  - Diaries [19 volumes], 1891–1915 (Offsite-box 61, Enclosure A)
  - Diaries [18 volumes], 1916–1936 (Offsite-box 61, Enclosure B)
  - Diaries [13 volumes], 1937–1949 (Offsite-box 61, Enclosure C)
- Series IV. Scrapbooks, 1894–1944
  - George du Maurier, 1894–1948 (Offsite-box 62, Volume 1)
    Franco-British cartoonist and author of the Gothic novel "Trilby" (1895), which featured the character Svengali.
  - New York City 250th anniversary, 1915 June 24 (Offsite-box 60, Folder 15)
    Envelope of correspondence, programs, invitations, etc. As described by Paltsits: "250th anniversary of the installation of the first Mayor and Board of Aldermen of the City of New York, on June 24, 1665. And the adoption of the official flag on June 24, 1915."
  - Honorary Doctor of Letters, Brown University (June 15, 1936), 1935–1936 (Offsite-box 62, Volume 2)
  - Honorary Doctor of Letters, Rutgers University (June 12, 1938) (Offsite-box 62, Volume 3)
  - Rutgers University, 175th Anniversary Commencement, 1941 (Offsite-box 60, Folder 16)
  - Retirement from New York Public Library, 1937–1941 (Offsite-box 71 (flat), Volume 1)
    As described by Paltsits: "SCRAP BOOK, Giving the history and correspondence, with newspaper and other articles, of the retirement from the New York Public Library, containing some fine autograph letters of distinguished scholars and public men, etc."
  - Birthday cards, 1941 July 12 (Offsite-box 62, Volume 4)
    As described by Paltsits: "Greetings on my seventy-fourth birthday, July 12, 1941, my first birthday after retirement from N.Y.P.L."
  - Golden wedding anniversary [2 folders], 1941 July 21 (Offsite-box 60, Folder 17–18)
    As described by Paltsits: "Golden Wedding of Victor Hugo and Anne (Müller) Paltsits, 1891-1941, 50th Anniversary Album of Greetings."
  - Wife's death, 1944 (Offsite-box 71 (flat), Volume 2)
    As described by Paltsits: "In Memoriam Anne (Müller) Paltsits / b. August 25, 1871; d. June 29, 1944 / Interred July 3, 1944 in the Woodlawn Cemetery, Bronx, N.Y."
- Series V. Publications, 1825–1951
  - Works by Paltsits, 1900–1951 (Offsite-box 63)
    Listed chronologically.
    ___The Captivity of John Gyles, 1689–1698 (1900)
    ___A Bibliography of the Separate & Collected Works of Philip Freneau, Together with an Account of His Newspaper (1903)
    ___New York Considered and Improved, 1695, by John Miller. With Introduction and Notes by Victor Hugo Paltsits (1903) [2 copies]
    ___The Depredation at Pemaquid in August, 1689, and Events That Led Up To It (1905) [2 copies]
    ___Scheme for the Conquest of Canada in 1746 (1905) [3 copies]
    ___Plea for the Nationalization of the Site of Fort Ticonderoga (1908)
    ___The Function of State Historian of New York (1909) [2 copies]
    ___The Manuscript Division in the New York Public Library, Bulletin of the New York Public Library, vol. 19, no. 2 (February 1915)
    ___A Pilgrimage to Salem in 1838 by a Southern Admirer of Nathaniel Hawthorne (1916)
    ___Cruise of the U.S. Brig Argus in 1813: Journal of Surgeon James Inderwick (1917) [6 copies]
    ___Letters of American Clergymen, 1711 to 1860 (1917)
    ___Papers and Proceedings of the Drake Memorial Celebration, May 29, 1915, Together with a Bibliography of the Writings of Dr. Joseph Rodman Drake by Victor Hugo Paltsits (1919) [2 versions]
    ___John Holt, Public Printer of New York, to the President of the Senate (1922)
    ___An Exhibition of Bibles of Ancient and Modern Times in Various Languages (1923)
    ___A Hitherto Unknown Edition of the Jesuit Huron Relation of 1648–1649. A Bibliographical Description (1923) [2 copies]
    ___Inventory of the Rensselaerswyck Manuscripts (1924)
    ___Two Important Gifts to the New York Public Library by Mr. George F. Baker, Jr.: Columbus' Letter on the Discovery of America (1493–1497) & Daniel Denton's Description of New York in 1670 (1924)
    ___The Founding of New Amsterdam in 1626 (1925) [3 copies]
    ___Wilberforce Eames: A Bio-bibliographical Narrative (1925) [2 copies + galley proofs]
    ___Libraries as Publishers and Promoters of Scholarship (1926) [7 copies]
    ___The New York Tercentenary: An Exhibition of the History of New Netherland, 1524–1674 (1926)
    ___Family Correspondence of Herman Melville, 1830–1904, in the Gansevoort-Lansing Collection, Bulletin of the New York Public Library, vol. 33, no. 7 (July 1929)
    ___Family Correspondence of Herman Melville, 1830–1904, in the Gansevoort-Lansing Collection (Concluded), Bulletin of the New York Public Library, vol. 33, no. 8 (August 1929) [2 copies]
    ___Family Correspondence of Herman Melville, 1830–1904, in the Gansevoort-Lansing Collection (1929) [3 copies]
    ___A Renaissance Illuminated Manuscript of Valerius Maximus, Bulletin of the New York Public Library, vol. 33, no. 12 (December 1929)
    ___Narrative of American Voyages and Travels of Captain William Owen, R.N., and Settlement of the Island of Campobello in the Bay of Fundy, 1766–1771 in Bulletin of the New York Public Library, vol. 35, nos. 2–3, 5, 9 (February-October 1931) [2 sets]
    ___Journal of Robert Rogers the Ranger on his Expedition for Receiving the Capitulation of Western French Posts (October 20, 1760 to February 14, 1761), Bulletin of the New York Public Library, vol. 37, no. 4 (April 1933) + offprint
    ___Judge Augustus Porter, Pioneer of Niagara Falls, With an Account of His Business Day Book of 1818 to 1822 (1937)
    ___The Miracle of Books and the New York Public Library (1937)
    ___Bibliography, the Correct Description of Books (1939) [circa 56 copies]
    ___Dongan Charter to Jamaica of 1686: Its Antecedents and Implications (1940) [2 copies]
    ___Narrative of American Voyages and Travels of Captain William Owen, R.N., and Settlement of the Island of Campobello in the Bay of Fundy, 1766–1771 (1942) [2 copies]
    ___The Lenox-Quartich Transactions, 1874–1880, Papers of the Bibliographical Society of America, vol. 40, 3rd quarter (1946)
    ___New Light on 'Publick Occurrences,' America's First Newspaper (1950)
    ___The Honorable John Boyd Thacher, Man of Versatility (1951) [3 copies]
    ___A Notable Gift of Two American Manuscripts (undated)
    ___Herman Melville's Background and New Light on the Publication of Typee (undated) [2 copies]
  - Works by Paltsits, 1919 (Offsite-box 72)
    ___Papers and Proceedings of the Drake Memorial Celebration, May 29, 1915, Together with a Bibliography of the Writings of Dr. Joseph Rodman Drake by Victor Hugo Paltsits (1919)
  - Works by others (A), 1831–1951 (Offsite-box 64)
    Listed alphabetically by author or title.
    ___Adams, John Quincy. Speech of John Quincy Adams, of Massachusetts, Upon the Right of the People, Men and Women, to Petition; on the Freedom of Speech and of Debate... (1838)
    ___Adams, Randolph G. The Case of the Columbus Letter (1939)
    ___Addresses of the Twenty-seventh Synod of the Fifth Province of the Protestant Episcopal Church in the United States of America (1950)
    ___American Bible Society. The Holy Bible, Containing the Old and New Testaments (1921)
    ___American Book-Prices Current, vol. 54 (1947–48)
    ___American Library Association. Friends of the Library Groups (1935)
    ___American Philosophical Society. A Catalogue of Manuscript and Printed Documents, Chiefly Americana, Selected from the Archives and Manuscript Collections (1937)
    ___American Swedish Historical Museum. A Quarter Century of Progress, 1926–1951 (1951?) [2 copies]
    ___Anderson Galleries. Historical Relics of George Washington Inherited and Collected by Mr. William Lanier Washington (1917)
    ___Anderson, John J. A Junior Class History of the United States (1876)
    ___Andrews, Charles M. "God's Protecting Providence," Florida Historical Quarterly, vol. 21, no. 2 (October 1942)
    ___Andrews, Charles M. "On the Writing of Colonial History," William and Mary Quarterly, vol. 1, no. 1 (January 1944)
    ___Andrews, Evangeline Walker and Charles McLean Andrews, eds. Jonathan Dickinson's Journal, or, God's Protecting Providence. Being the Narrative of a Journey from Port Royal in Jamaica to Philadelphia between August 23, 1696 and April 1, 1697 (1945)
    ___Art Treasures from the Vienna Collections (1949–1950)
    ___Auditor's Report on the Finances (1831)
    ___Avery, Elroy McKendree. A History of the United States and its People From Their Earliest Records to the Present Time, vols. 1–3 (1904–10)
  - Works by others (A, continued), 1948–1951 (Offsite-box 72)
    ___Autograph Collectors' Journal
    • vol. 1, no. 1 (October 1948) [2]
    • vol. 1, no. 2 (January 1949)
    • vol. 1, no. 3 (April 1949)
    • vol. 1, no. 4 (July 1949) [4]
    • vol. 2, no. 1 (October 1949) [5]
    • vol. 2, no. 2 (January 1950)
    • vol. 2, no. 3 (April 1950)
    • vol. 2, no. 4 (July 1950)
    • vol. 3, no. 1 (October 1950)
    • vol. 3, no. 2 (January 1951) [4]
    • vol. 3, no. 3 (April 1951) [4]
  - Works by others (A-B), 1902–1948 (Offsite-box 65)
    ___Avery, Elroy McKendree. A History of the United States and its People From Their Earliest Records to the Present Time, vols. 4–7 (1904–10)
    ___Bassett, Edward M. The Government of Congregational Churches in the State of New York (1927)
    ___Beecher, Willis J. Historicity (1902)
    ___The Bibliographical Society, 1892–1942: Studies in Retrospect (1945)
    ___Bloch, Joshua. The New Latin Version of the Psalter (1948)
    ___Botstiber, Hugo. Musicalia in der New York public Library (1903)
    ___Boyd, Julian P. The Scheide Library (1947)
    ___Bronx Sunday School Association. Year Book (1906–07)
    ___Brown, Robert Benaway. The Netherlands and America (1947)
    ___Burpee, Lawrence J. and Arthur G. Doughty, eds. Index and Dictionary of Canadian History (1911)
  - Works by others (B), 1945–1950 (Offsite-box 72)
    ___Bibliographical Society annual reports, 1945/46–1949/50
  - Works by others (C), 1904 (Offsite-box 72)
    ___Collections of the New Brunswick Historical Society, No. 5 (1904)
  - Works by others (C-H), 1835–1951 (Offsite-box 66)
    ___Cahoon, Herbert. Herman Melville. A Check List of Books and Manuscripts in the Collections of the New York Public Library (1951)
    ___Christian Faith in Action. The Churches Working Together (undated)
    ___Cushing, Luther S. Manual of Parliamentary Practice. Rules of Proceeding and Debate in Deliberative Assemblies (1870)
    ___Denton, Daniel. A Brief Description of New York, Formerly Called New Netherlands, 1670 (1902)
    ___Die Bermyde Psalms In gebruik by die drie Hollandse (Afrikaanse) kerke in Suid-Afrika... (1937)
    ___Drake, Joseph Rodman. The Culprit Fay and Other Poems (1835)
    ___Drake, Joseph Rodman. The Culprit Fay and Other Poems (1923)
    ___Eames, Wilberforce. Description of a Wood Engraving Illustrating the South American Indians (1505) (1922)
    ___Eberstadt, Lindley. Early Oregon Imprints at Yale (1950)
    ___Eggleston, Edward. The Transit of Civilization from England to America in the Seventeenth Century (1901)
    ___Engineers' Club. Annual Report (1937)
    ___Facsimiles & Forgeries: A Guide to a Timely Exhibition in the William L. Clements Library (1950)
    ___Favorite Illustrated Dictionary, Containing Over 32,000 Words and Phrases, and Illustrated With 670 Engravings (1882)
    ___Fox, Dixon Ryan. Herbert Levi Osgood, An American Scholar (1924)
    ___Fulton, J. F. Humanism in Bibliography: An Appreciation of Leonard Mackall, Georgia Historical Quarterly, vol. 22, no. 1 (March 1938)
    ___Fulton, Robert I. and Thomas C. Trueblood, compilers. Choice Readings from Standard and Popular Authors (1897)
    ___Ganong, William Francis. Dochet (St. Croix Island): A Monograph (1902)
    ___Ganong, William Francis. Ste. Croix (Dochet) Island (1945)
    ___A General Note of the Prices of Binding all Sorts of Books, 1669 (1951)
    ___Gray, George W. The Advancing Front of Medicine (1941)
    ___Guia de personas que cultivan la historia de America (1951)
    ___Gurley, Fred G. What Do You Want... How Do You Expect to Get It? (1949)
    ___Hall, G. Stanley. Children's Reading: As a Factor in Their Education (1908) [2 copies]
    ___Harvard University. Bibliographical Contributions (1905)
    ___[Hell Gate] Notes sur lest travaux de Hell Gate (1877)
    ___Hossfeld's Dutch Dialogues, and Idiomatic Phrases Indispensable for a Rapid Acquisition and Correct Expression of the Dutch Language (1894)
  - Works by others (J-M), 1862–1951 (Offsite-box 67)
    ___Jameson, J. Franklin. Dictionary of United States History, 1492–1898 (1894–97)
    ___Jefferson, Charles E. What the War is Teaching (1916)
    ___Jefferson, Charles E. Five Present-Day Controversies (1924)
    ___Jefferson, Charles E. Nature Sermons (1925)
    ___Jefferson, Charles E. Five World Problems (1928)
    ___Jefferson, Charles E. The Next Step (undated)
    ___Johnston, John. A History of the Towns of Bristol and Bremen in the State of Maine, Including the Pemaquid Settlement (1873)
    ___Jones, Joseph. Humor in Moby Dick (1945–46)
    ___Kellar, Herbert A. Where are the Historical Manuscripts? (1950)
    ___Kupka, August. History of Flushing, N.Y. The Colonial Period (1948?)
    ___Kupka, August. History of Flushing, N.Y. During the Nineteenth Century (1949)
    ___Kupka, August. History of Flushing, N.Y. A Survey of Its Progress During the First Half of the Twentieth Century, 1901–1950 [2 copies] (1950)
    ___Laćy, Ernest de. Dicther-Perlen (1951)
    ___Larremore, Thomas A. An American Typographic Tragedy—the Imprints of Frederick Conrad Bursch (1949)
    ___Larsen, Henry. The North-West Passage, 1940–1942 and 1944 (1948)
    ___Leary, Lewis, ed. The First Biography of Philip Freneau (1947)
    ___Leete, Frederick D. Christianity in Science (1928)
    ___Lockwood, George R. The Art of Elocution as an Essential Part of Rhetoric, 4th edition (1867)
    ___MacDonald, James M. Two Centuries in the History of the Presbyterian Church, Jamaica, L.I.; The Oldest Existing Church, of the Presbyterian Name, in America (1862)
    ___Macduff, J. R. The Mind and Words of Jesus; and The Faithful Promiser ([1883])
    ___Manual for Church Officers and Members of the Government, Discipline, and Worship of the Presbyterian Church in the United States of America. Ninth edition (1939)
    ___Marsh, Philip M. Freneau and Jefferson: The Poet-Editor Speaks for Himself About the National Gazette Episode (1936)
    ___Marsh, Philip M. Philip Freneau and His Circle (1939)
    ___Marsh, Philip M. Philip Freneau's Personal File of the Freeman's Journal (1939)
    ___Marsh, Philip M. The Griswold Story of Freneau and Jefferson (1945)
    ___Marsh, Philip M. Jefferson's "Conduct" of the National Gazette (1945)
    ___Marsh, Philip M. The Vindication of Mr. Jefferson (1946)
    ___Marsh, Philip M. Was Freneau a Fighter? (undated)
    ___Marsh, Philip M. and Milton Ellis. Freneau's Last Home (1939)
    ___Maury, Max. Laird & Lee's Vest-Pocket Littré-Webster English-French Anglais-Francais and French-English Francais-Anglais Dictionary (1918)
    ___Mayfield, John S. The Luck of an Autograph Collector (1950)
    ___McAfee, Cleland Boyd. The Ruling Elder: His Duties and His Opportunities (1939)
    ___McAnear, Beverly. American Imprints Concerning King's College (1950)
    ___McDonald, Gerald D. William Bradford's Book Trade and John Bowne, Long Island Quaker, as his Book Agent, 1686–1691 (1951)
  - Works by others (N-S), 1825–1951 (Offsite-box 68)
    ___Nelson, Charles Alexander. Selected Poems (undated)
    ___New Jersey Historical Society. Charter, By-Laws, List of Members (1950)
    ___The New Life Movement (undated)
    ___[New York Dry Dock Company] A Statement in Relation to the Concerns of the New-York Dry Dock Company (1825)
    ___New York Library Club. Manual (1907)
    ___New York Library Club. Manual of the New York Library Club, 1885–1945 (1946)
    ___New York Public Library. Bulletin of the New York Public Library, Index to Volumes 41–50 (1948)
    ___Owen, William. The Journal of Captain William Owen, R. N., During His Residence on Campobello in 1770–1771, Together With Other Documents and Notes on the Historiy of the Island, edited by W. F. Ganong (1897)
    ___Owen, William. The Journal of Captain William Owen, R. N., During His Residence on Campobello in 1770–1771, edited by W. F. Ganong (1899)
    ___Pageant of America: A Pictorial History of the Unites States [prospectus] (1925–1926)
    ___Pargellis, Stanley. The Corporation and The Historian (1944)
    ___Parker, Donald Dean. Local History: How to Gather It, Write It, and Publish It (1944)
    ___Penniman, James Hosmer. George Washington at Mount Vernon on the Potomac (1921)
    ___Pennypacker, Morton. The Duke's Laws: Their Antecedents, Implications and Importance (1944)
    ___Phillips, Mary E. James Fenimore Cooper (1913)
    ___Pleadwell, Frank Lester. James Inderwick, Surgeon, United States Navy, 1813–1815 (1922)
    ___Pleadwell, Frank Lester. The Life and Works of Joseph Rodman Drake (1935)
    ___Potter, David. "Reviews of Moby-Dick," The Journal of the Rutgers University Library, vol. 3, no. 2 (June 1940)
    ___Potter, David. "The Brodhead Diaries, 1846–1849," The Journal of the Rutgers University Library, vol. 11, no. 1 (December 1947)
    ___Queens Golden Anniversary Exhibition of Arts and Crafts (1948)
    ___Queensboro Society of Arts and Crafts Annual Outdoor Exhibit (1951)
    ___Raymond, Rossiter W. Peter Cooper (1901)
    ___Record of the Conference on Law, Medicine and the Unstable Family (1949)
    ___Report of the Special Committee of the Board of Aldermen on the Two Hundred and Fiftieth Anniversary of the Installation of the First Mayor and Board of Aldermen of the City of New York (1915)
    ___Representative Reviews of "Church and State in the United States" by Anson Phelps Stokes (1950–1951)
    ___[Rich, O.] Catalogue of a Collection of Manuscripts Principally in Spanish, Relating to America, in the Possession of O. Rich (1894?)
    ___Riley, Woodbridge, Frederick W. Peabody, and Charles E. Humiston. The Faith, The Falsity and The Failure of Christian Science (1925)
    ___Riley, Woodbridge. From Myth to Reason: The Story of the March of Mind in the Interpretation of Nature (1926)
    ___Rochedieu, Charles Alfred. "Bibliography of French Translations of English Works: 1700–1800," offprint from Romanic Review, vol. 41, no. 2 (April 1950)
    ___Rochester Museum of Arts and Sciences. Annual Report (1948)
    ___[Rochester.] Looking at Your City... (1948)
    ___Rodgers, Cleveland, and Rebecca B. Rankin. "Greater New York's First Birthday," New-York Historical Society Quarterly, vol. 32, no. 1 (January 1948)
    ___Rogers, Ernest E. Connecticut's Naval Office at New London During the War of the American Revolution (1933)
    ___St. Catherine's Monastery on Mount Sinai (1950)
    ___Schellenberg, Theodore R. European Archival Practices in Arranging Records (1939)
    ___Schindler, Margaret Castle. "Fictitious Biography," Journal of the New York Botanical Garden, vol. 20 (September 1919)
    ___Schnitzler, J. M. Hossfeld's New Practical Method for Learning the Dutch Language (1902)
    ___Schuyler, Robert Livingston. The Usefulness of Useless History (1941)
    ___Schwenke, Paul. Zentralblatt für Bibliothekswesen Begründet von Otto Hartwig (1910)
    ___Scott, Eleanor Bryce. Early Literary Clubs in New York City (1933)
    ___Sealts, Merton M. Jr. "Melville's Reading: A Check-List of Books Owned and Borrowed," offprint from Harvard Library Bulletin (1948–1950)
    ___Serís, Homero. Una Nueva Variedad de la Edición Príncipe del "Quijote" (1918)
  - Works by others (S), 1905 (Offsite-box 72)
    ___O. G. Sonneck, Francis Hopkinson: The First American Poet-Composer (1737–1791), and James Lyon: Patriot, Preacher, Psalmodist (1735–1794); Two Studies in Early American Music (1905)
  - Works by others (S-W), 1838–1949 (Offsite-box 69)
    ___Simms, P. Marion. The Bible from the Beginning (1929)
    ___Smith, Wilbur M. Therefore, Stand: A Plea for a Vigorous Apologetic in the Present Crisis of Evangelical Christianity (1945)
    ___Sonneck, O. G. Francis Hopkinson (1737–1791), The First American Composer (1903)
    ___Sonneck, O. G. Early American Operas (1904/5)
    ___The Southern Rose [periodical], vol. 6, no. 4 (14 October 1837)–vol. 6, no. 26 (18 August 1838)
    ___Stedman, Edmund Clarence. Poems, Lyrical and Idyllic (1860) [2 copies]
    ___Stokes, I. N. Phelps, New York Past and Present: Its History and Landmarks, 1524–1939 (1939)
    ___Supplément du cinquième livre de l'histoire de Tacite (undated)
    ___Taylor, Hugh Stott, Ernest O. Lawrence, and Irving Langmuir. Molecular Films, The Cyclotron and The New Biology (1942, 1946)
    ___[Thomas, George C.] Autographs, Rare Books and Fine Bindings, the Collection of the Late George C. Thomas (1924)
    ___Thomas, Isaiah. The History of Printing in America, With a Biography of Printers, and an Account of Newspapers, 2 volumes (1874)
    ___Tout, T. F. Some Conflicting Tendencies in English Administrative History During the Fourteenth Century (1924)
    ___Van Hoesen, Henry Bartlett. Brown University Library. The Library of the College or University in the English Colony of Rhode Island and Providence Plantations in New England in America, 1767–1782 (1939)
    ___Weaks, Mabel. "Long Ago and 'Faraway': Traces of Melville in the Marquesas in the Journal of A. G. Jones, 1854–1855," Bulletin of the New York Public Library, vol. 52, no. 7 (July 1948)
    ___Weaks, Mabel. "Some Ancestral Lines of Herman Melville as Traced in Funeral and Memorial Spoons," New York Genealogical and Biographical Record, vol. 80, no. 4 (October 1949)
    ___Webster, John Clarence. Joseph Frederick Wallet Des Barres and the Atlantic Neptune (1927)
    ___Webster, John Clarence. Catalogue of the John Clarence Webster Canadiana Collection (Pictorial Section), New Brunswick Museum (1939)
    ___Webster, John Clarence. An Historical Guide to New Brunswick (1944)
    ___Webster, John Clarence. Those Crowded Years, 1863–1944: An Octogenarian's Record of Work (1944)
    ___Who's Who in Queens, 1936–1937 (1936)
    ___Winans, George Woodruff. First Presbyterian Church of Jamaica, New York, 1662–1942. A Narrative History of its Two Hundred and Eighty Years of Continuous Service (1943)
    ___Wroth, Lawrence C. Some American Contributions to the Art of Navigation, 1519–1802 (1947)
    ___[Wroth, Lawrence C.] In Retrospect, 1923–1949: An Exhibition commemorating twenty-six years of service to The John Carter Brown Library by Lawrence C. Wroth, Librarian (1949)
  - Works by others (T), 1906, 1910, 1914 (Offsite-box 72)
    ___Transactions of the Bronx Society of Arts and Sciences, vol. 1, parts I-III (1906, 1910, 1914)